
NAME
    .\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1
    
SYNOPSIS
    RWExport-To-HTML.ps1
    by EightBitz
    Version 0.9.1b
    2017-01-29, 10:00 AM CST
    
    RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 transforms a Realm Works export file into a formatted HTML file. The formatted HTML file relies on a 
    "RWExport_091b.css" file for formatting information.
    
    LICENSE:
    This script is now licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution + Non-Commercial license.
       
    Basically, that means:
       -You are free to share and adapt the script.
       -When sharing the script, you must give appropriate credit and indicate if changes were made.
    
       Summary: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/
       Legal Code: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode
    
    IMPORTANT:
    You will likely have to change your execution policy to run this script. You can do that with the following command:
    
       Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned
    
    You may have to be logged in as a local administrator to do this, or run at least use the "Run as Administrator" option 
    when opening PowerShell (you can do this with a right-click).
    Please do NOT set the execution policy to "Unrestricted". If you still have issues after setting it to "RemoteSigned", 
    then you can open this script as a text file, select all, copy, and paste it into a new text file. Once you do that, 
    delete the old file, and rename the new one to "RWExport-To-HTML.ps1".
    
    IMPORTANT:
    The export from Realm Works must done with the "Compact Output" option. This script will likely not work with a "Full 
    Export".
    You can still export your full realm if you like, but make sure you do so with the "Compact Output" option.
    
    IMPORTANT:
    Make sure that the HTML file and the RWExport_091b.css file are in the same directory, otherwise, the HTML file will have 
    no formatting.
    For more information about this, type:
    
       Get-Help .\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -full
    
    And see the NOTES section.
    
    
SYNTAX
    .\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 [-Source] <String> [-Destination] <String> 
    [-Sort <Int32>] [-Prefix] [-Suffix] [-Details] [-Indent] [-SeparateSnippets] [-InlineStats] [-SimpleImageScale <Int32>] 
    [-SmartImageScale <Int32>] [-KeepStyles] [-ExtractFiles] [-CSSFileName <String>] [-SplitTopics] [-Log <String>] 
    [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 loads the XML file exported from Realm Works and transforms it into formatted HTML so it can be 
    printed or imported/pasted into other programs. The export from Realm Works must done with the Compact Output option.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Source <String>
        Enter the full path and filename for the source file (the Realm Works export file).
        
        IMPORTANT: This must be the first parameter on the command line.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    2
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Destination <String>
        Enter the full path and filename for the destination file (the HTML output).
        
        IMPORTANT: This must be the second parameter on the command line.
        (As long as the source and destination parameters are the first two, the remaining parameters are optional and can be 
        used in any order.)
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    3
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Sort <Int32>
        Choose your preferred sort order for exported topics.
           1 = Name
           2 = Prefix, Name **Default**
           3 = Category, Name
           4 = Category, Prefix, Name
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                2
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Prefix [<SwitchParameter>]
        Include this parameter to display the prefix for each topic. If you've entered prefixes for your topics in Realm 
        Works, this option will add them to the display in the HTML file in the form of "Prefix - Topic Name".
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Suffix [<SwitchParameter>]
        Include this parameter to display the suffix for each topic. If you've entered suffixes for your topics in Realm 
        Works, this option will add them to the display in the HTML file in the form of "Topic Name (Suffix)".
        If you include both the Prefix and Suffix parameters, the result will be "Prefix - Topic Name (Suffix)".
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Details [<SwitchParameter>]
        Include this parameter to include topic details (Category, Parent, Linkage, Tags, etc ...)
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Indent [<SwitchParameter>]
        Include this parameter to indent nested topics and section headers.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -SeparateSnippets [<SwitchParameter>]
        Include this parameter to display a line between snippets.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -InlineStats [<SwitchParameter>]
        Display Statblocks inline.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -SimpleImageScale <Int32>
        Include this parameter to scale the display size, by percentage, of embedded simple pictures.
        If you omit this parameter or if you set it to 0, only the thumbnail will display.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                0
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -SmartImageScale <Int32>
        Include this parameter to scale the display size, by percentage, of embedded smart images (usually maps).
        If you omit this parameter or if you set it to 0, only the thumbnail will display.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                0
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -KeepStyles [<SwitchParameter>]
        By default, this script strips some (not all) formatting from the imported data. It does this to allow formatting to 
        be controlled by the the CSS file. Otherwise, the inline formatting will override the settings in the CSS file.
        If you want to keep the original formatting, though, you can use this option.
        Right now, the format options that are stripped are: font, font size, font color and background color.
        Note that the CSS file has different definitions for regular snippet text, bulleted lists, numbered lists and tables.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -ExtractFiles [<SwitchParameter>]
        By default, this script creates one, single HTML file, with any file attachments encoded and embedded in the same, 
        single HTML file.
        If you wish, you can override this with the -ExtractFiles parameter. Including this on the command line will tell the 
        script to save attachments as separate files.
        If you include this option on the command line, you must specify a folder name for the destination instead of a file 
        name. The HTML file will be stored in the folder you specify, and each file will be stored in a subfolder name 
        "realm_files".
        Also note that both the destination folder and the "realm_files" subfolder must already exist. The script will not 
        create them for you.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -CSSFileName <String>
        By default, the HTML output file looks for "RWExport_091b.css" to define its style. You can use this option to 
        specify a different name.
        If you have two realms called Realm1 and Realm2, and you want each HTML output to have different fonts, font sizes or 
        colors, you can specify a name or "realma.css" for one file and "realmb.css" for the other.
        Not that this option does not create the file. It just tells the HTML file which filename to look for.
        For now, at least, you will have to manually copy RWExport_091b.css or some other css file you like and make whatever 
        changes you wish.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                RWExport_091b.css
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -SplitTopics [<SwitchParameter>]
        Save each topic as a separate HTML file.
        If you include this option on the command line, you must specify a folder name for the destination instead of a file 
        name. Each topic will be stored as an individual file within the folder you specify.
        Also note that the folder must already exist. The script will not create it for you.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Log <String>
        Specify the path for an optional log file.
           [NOT WORKING YET]
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer, PipelineVariable, and OutVariable. For more information, see 
        about_CommonParameters (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113216). 
    
INPUTS
    The .rwexport file from a Realm Works export that was created with the "Compact Output" option. This can an export of a 
    full realm or a custom or partial export, just so long as it's made with the "Compact Output" option.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    An HTML file that uses an external style sheet for formatting. The external style sheet should be named 
    "RWExport_091b.css" and should be in the same folder as the HTML output. The RWExport_091b.css file will not be generated 
    by this script, but should already exist.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        SORTING:
        
        The specified sort order will occur regardless of whether or not prefixes are included.
        If you sort by prefix, but do not include the -Prefix parameter, your topics will still be sorted by prefix, even 
        though the prefix won't be displayed.
        Likewise, if you sort by Name, but do include the -Prefix parameter, your topics will still be sorted by name, even 
        though the prefix will be displayed.
        
        It appears that topics will always be sorted under their containers. In other words, topics that are not in 
        containers will be sorted relative to each other. Contained topics will be sorted relative to their peers within that 
        container.
        
        
        
        TIPS ON MANAGING COMMANDLINE OPTIONS:
        
        There are a several commandline options for this script, and that can probably be intimidating to some people. Here 
        is my recommended starting point:
        
           c:\<full path>\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source C:\<full path>\MyExport.rwoutput -Destination c:\<full 
        path>\MyHTML.html -Indent -Prefix -Suffix -Sort 2
        
        2 is the default sort value, so if that's what you want, you don't have to specify it, but I'm doing so anyway just 
        to be clear as to what's happening in this example.
        
        If you like the output from this combination of options, you don't have to rememeber to type this out all the time. 
        You can save it as it's own PowerShell script. Paste the command into it's own .ps1 file. Name it something like 
        "MyExportOptions.ps1". (Make sure to replace <full path> with the actual path for where the relevant files are.)
        
        But you don't have to stop there. Say you have three different realms, and you want to specify different options for 
        each. You can do something like this:
        
           c:\<full path>\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source C:\<full path>\Pathfinder-Realm.rwoutput -Destination c:\<full 
        path>\Pathfinder-Realm.html -Indent -Prefix -Suffix -Sort 2
        
           c:\<full path>\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source C:\<full path>\SavageWorlds-Realm.rwoutput -Destination c:\<full 
        path>\SavageWorlds-Realm.html -Indent -InlineStats
        
           c:\<full path>\RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source C:\<full path>\FATE-Realm.rwoutput -Destination c:\<full 
        path>\FATE-Realm.html -SimpleImageScale 25 -SmartImageScale 50
        
        You can put all three of those command lines in the same PowerShell script and call it "ConvertAllMyExports.ps1".
        
        Or you can put each command line in its own script called "ConvertPathfinderExport.ps1", 
        "ConvertSavageWorldsExport.ps1" and "ConvertFATEExport.ps1"
        
        Now, when you want convert a given export, you don't have to remember all the command line options, because you 
        already have your favorite ones ready to go. You just run your PowerShell script instead of this one, and yours will 
        invoke this one with your favorite options.
        
        As a side note, you can set up a separate folder for each export, and put a different RWExport_091b.css file in each 
        folder, so you can give each export a completely different look (by editing the RWExport_091b.css file in each 
        folder).
        
        
        
        AND SPEAKING OF RWExport_091b.css:
        
        This script and its resulting HTML file assume the existence of a file named "RWExport_091b.css". If this file is not 
        in the same folder as the resulting HTML file, it will not display correctly.
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html
    
    This is the most basic example.
    This would give you the most basic output. The text would be formatted according to Title, Topic, Section and Snippet, 
    and that's about it. Nothing much more than that.
    
    Topics will be sorted by prefix first, then by name.
    Topics will be listed by name only with no prefixes or suffixes.
    Nested topics and sections will not be indented. Everything will be left-justified.
    Statblocks will not be displayed inline.
    Simple Pictures and Smart Images will be displayed as thumbnails.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -Sort 1
    
    Choose your preferred sort order for exported topics. The example above will sort topics by their names.
    
    Valid options are:
       1 = Sort by topic names
       2 = Sort by topic prefixes first, then by topic names (this is the default value)
       3 = Sort by topic category first, then by topic name
       4 = Sort by topic category first, then by topic prefix, then by topic name
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -Prefix
    
    Prepend topic prefixes to topic names.
    
    If a topic has a prefix of "Dungeon 1" and a name of "Room 3", you would include the Prefix parameter to list the topic 
    in the output as "Dungeon 1 - Room 3"
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -Suffix
    
    Append topic suffixes to topic names.
    
    If a topic has a suffix of "Mess Hall" and a name of "Room 3", you would include the Suffix parameter to list the topic 
    in the output as "Room 3 (Mess Hall)"
    
    If you include the prefix and suffix parameter, the topic would be displayed as "Dungeon 1 - Room 3 (Mess Hall)"
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -Indent
    
    To give your output just a little more style, you can choose to indent subsections and contained topics.
    This looks really nice for documents that have content that might be nested 2 or 3 levels in, but for documents that 
    might have 4, 5 or 6 levels of nested topics and subsections, it might not look so great.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 6 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -InlineStats
    
    By default, stat blocks will not display inline, but will instead offer a clickable link where you can then see the full 
    stat block.
    
    If you want everything in one view, though, without having to click, you can use the -InlineStats option.
    
    Inline stat blocks will not always look as nice as you might like, but this parameter gives you the option to include 
    them if you like.
    
    Also, if you include both -Indent and -InlineStats, the stat blocks will NOT indent. That prospect was fraught with too 
    many headaches.
    
    As far as "looking nice", the clickable links are the better option, but if you want everything viewable in one document, 
    this gives you that option.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 7 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -SimpleImageScale 50
    
    Display simple images inline at 50% of the width of the page.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 8 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>RWExport-To-HTML.ps1 -Source MyExport.rwoutput -Destination MyHTML.html -SmartImageScale 50
    
    Display smart images inline at 50% of the width of the page.
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS



